Hey, Kaito.
Who the hell is Makata Jin?
（逆之上ギャモン）おい　カイト。→
真方ジンってぇのは
一体　何者なんだ？→
What's he got to do with the Master Brains?
あの　マスターブレインってやつとの
関係は？→
Hey! We were almost killed by a Master Brain who claimed to follow Makata Jin!
おい！
俺たちは　真方ジンを信奉する
マスターブレインの一人に→
Jin's got nothing to do with those Master Brains.
殺されかけたんだぞ！
（大門カイト）ジンは
あいつらとは関係ねえ。
Dangerous person detected. Dangerous person detected.
（イワシミズ君）
危険人物　感知。　危険人物　感知。
Iwashimizu, I told you that Gammon's not dangerous.
（カイト　ギャモン　キュービック・Ｇ）ん？
（キュービック）イワシミズ君。
ギャモンは危険人物じゃないって。
Cubik, I think your Iwashimizu's acting up a lot lately.
（ギャモン）チッ。　おい　キュービック。→
Not really...
その　イワシミズってぇの
調子悪いんじゃねえのか？
（キュービック）そんな事ないと
思うんだけどなあ。
Jinjin?
I Still Believe
（井藤ノノハ）うぅ…　あ～
持ちづらいし　前も見づらいし…。
I can't get a good hold of it, and I can't see where I'm going either...
あ～！　あっ…　おっとっと！
あれ？
（ジン）大丈夫かい？
ジンさん！
Are you okay?
Jin!
あ…　ありがとうございます。
私　先生に頼まれちゃって。
Thanks a lot!
A teacher asked me to sort this out.
I see.
いいんだよ。
これ全部　運ぶのは大変だ。
It seems like a lot to carry alone. Let me help.
俺も手伝おう。
あっ　大丈夫です。
I'm fine. I'm much stronger than I look.
私　こう見えて　力持ちだし。
よし！
Yup!
I can't get a good hold of it, and I can't see where I'm going either...
持ちづらいし　前も見づらいし…。
あっ！　お～っとっと…。
あれ？
Huh?
（レイツェル）こんにちは。
Hello.
So you say Makata Jin's got nothing to do with them?
（ギャモン）「真方ジンが
あいつらとは関係ねえ」。→
そう思う根拠は？
What do you base that on?
俺は　ジンを知ってる。
I know Jin. And I say he's got nothing to do with them, so you better believe it.
その俺が　関係ねえって言ったら
関係ねえんだ。
（ギャモン）ケッ。
んなこったろうと思ったぜ。
Thought it was something like that.
本人に確かめる。
I'm gonna ask him directly.
あぁ!?　ギャモン　お前！
おわっ！
Gammon, you little..!
（キュービック）
ちょっと　２人とも落ち着いて。
（イワシミズ君）不審者　検出…。
Calm down, guys!
What are you doing?
Suspicious element detected.
（レイツェル）何やってるの？
（３人）えっ？
転校してきたんだって。
She transferred to this school.
レイツェル！
（キュービック　ギャモン）あっ！
Raetsel?!
よろしく。
Let's get along.
（解道バロン）私としては　お断りする
理由はありませんからね。
I have no reason to reject your transfer.
こんなに早く　編入を認めて頂いて
感謝するわ。　解道バロン学園長。
Thanks for admitting me so quickly,
principal Kaidou Baron.
（バロン）アムギーネ共和国　エニグマ大統領
じきじきの頼みとあっては…。
It was a direct request from the president of the Republic of Amgine, Enigma.
そういう話　興味ないの。
I couldn't care less.
では　学園長として
１つだけ質問をしましょう。→
Then as the principal, I have one question for you:
なぜ　我が　√学園に？
Why did you choose Root Academy?
ジンには
足りないものがあるから。
Because Jin needs something.
（バロン）足りないもの？
Something?
私よ。
Me.
（相沢ユウイチ）武田さん
あの子　高１らしいっす！
Takeda, I heard that she's a high school freshman!
（武田ナオキ）高１か…。
こう言っちゃあ　なんだが→
A freshman, huh?
I must say, we get lots of hotties transferring here!
うちの学園に来る転校生は
美少女ばかりだな～。
（相沢）はい。　グッジョブ　学園長！
Yeah! Props to the principal!
おっ！　そうだ。　次の学園祭だが
我が　パズル部主催→
Oh, right! At the next school fair,
how about we of the Puzzle Club organize a Root Academy Pretty Girls' Puzzle Tournament?!
「√学園　美少女　勝ち抜きパズル！」
でも　やるか？
うぉ～!?
おぉ～！　なんか　聞いただけでも
燃えるっす　武田さん！
Takeda, just imagining that made me see rainbows!
だろ～？　相沢氏！
I know, right, Aizawa?!
（千枝乃タマキ）
はじめまして　レイツェルさん。
Hello, Raetsel.
（水谷アイリ）はじめまして。
Hello.
はじめまして。
私は　生徒会長の千枝乃タマキ。
I'm Chieno Tamaki, the president of the academy's student council.
√学園の事で　分からない事が
あったら　何でも聞いてね。
If there's anything you need help with, feel free to ask.
私は　姫川エレナよ。
あなた　ギヴァーよね？
I'm Himekawa Elena.
You're a Giver, right?
はい。
Yeah.
（タマキ）よく分かったわね　エレナさん。
How did you know, Elena?
勘ですよ　生徒会長。
ギヴァー同士の。
My intuition told me, prez.
We Givers recognize our own kind.
私は　水谷アイリです。
I'm Mizutani Airi.
よかったら　パズル部に
入りませんか？
パズル部？
Would you like to join the Puzzle Club?
Puzzle Club?
あ…　これは　「ぺろりんぽろりん
バケツパズル」っていって→
This is the Smiley bucket puzzle I made.
私が作ったんです。→
６体の　ぺろりんぽろりんを
み～んな　このバケツに入れて→
There are these six Smileys. You have to fit them all into the bucket.
蓋が　ちゃんと閉まれば
正解なんですが…。
It's solved if you can close the lid.
But actually, I can't solve it myself.
実は　私にも解けないんです。
Smile? What?
ぺろりんぽろりん　です。
I'm Smiley. Nice to meet you, Raetsel.
「はじめまして　レイツェルさん」。
ったく！
何で　俺が　段ボールを…　おっ？
Geez... Why do I have to carry-
Huh?
真方ジン。
Huh? Makata Jin.
はぁ？　ふん…。
心の声
（ギャモン）あいつ…
学園長とはダチだろう。→
He's best friends with the principal, isn't he?
何で隠れる？
Then why is he hiding?
ジン…。
Jin...
What do you want?
（ギャモン）目的は何だ？
てめえ
何か　たくらんでるんだろう？→
I bet you're scheming something.
わざわざ転校までしてきやがって。
You wouldn't transfer here for no reason.
待て！　逃がすか！
Hold it! You ain't going anywhere!
（ギャモン）
俺の目は　ごまかせねえぞ。→
You can't fool me.
あいつは…　真方ジンは…
パズルを愛する天使なのか!?→
What is Makata Jin?
Is he an angel who loves puzzles or a demon who detests them?
それとも　パズルを憎む悪魔なのか!?
ふ～ん。　つまり　君…　大門カイトを
信じていいか迷ってるわけ？
So you're not sure if you can believe Daimon Kaito?
Jin despises puzzles from the bottom of his heart.
ジンは　パズルを憎んでるわ。
心の底から。
私とカイト　どっちを信じるかは→
It's up to you to choose whether you believe Daimon Kaito or me.
君自身が決める事ね。
ギャモーン！
えっ？
Gammon!
What are you doing to a girl?!
女の子に　何してんのよ！
おぉ…。
レイツェル　お前…。
Raetsel, what?
心配しないで。
ジンには何もしないから。→
Don't worry. I won't lay a finger on Jin.
預けるって言ったでしょ。
私も知りたいのよ。
I told you, you can have him for now.
I too want to see if you can actually help him get back his memories.
君が　ジンの記憶を
取り戻せるかどうか…。
思うに…　あの子　恋してる。
I think... she's in love.
恋？
Love?
そんな　ちょろ甘な事　言ってると
大やけどするぜ。→
You're gonna burn your hands on that bubbly, cheesy love crap.
あいつら　何か隠してやがる。→
They're hiding something.
Raetsel... and probably Makata Jin too.
レイツェルと…　恐らく　真方ジンもな。
ジンは　そんなんじゃねえ！
Jin's not like that!
（ギャモン）じゃあ　あいつらの
言ってる事…。
フッフッフッフ…。
Then what? Is it all just lies?
How should I know?
大門カイト。
Daimon Kaito... Jin's gonna abuse that trust of yours a bit now.
See! That's my point exactly, dammit!
お前の　その信頼感
このジン様が利用してやる。
ジンは　俺に
パズルは敵じゃないって…。
Jin taught me that puzzles aren't my enemies...
パズルは友達なんだって事を
教えてくれた…。
That puzzles are my friends.
愚者のパズルに両親を殺され
冷たく暗い塊と化した　俺の心を→
My heart was frozen solid when my parents were killed in a Fools' Puzzle.
ジンと　ジンのパズルは→
Jin and his puzzles warmed it up and freed it from the ice.
温め　溶かしてくれた…。
回想
パズルとの出会いは
人との出会いなんだよ。→
Encounters with puzzles are encounters with people.
解いてやれ。
自由にしてやれ　パズルを…。
Solve them. Free them. Free all the puzzles.
パズルには罪がない。
The puzzles did nothing wrong.
それを作った人間に
罪があるんだ。
The people who made them were in the wrong.
大切なものは手放すな。　絶対に…。
Don't forget what's important. Ever.
回想
（ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド）
あ～あ　また行き止まりだ。
Another dead end!
We can't solve it like this...
これじゃあ　ゴールに行けないよ。
Ah, if you do this, a new path opens up!
こうやると
新しい道が出来るんだ！
ああ！
（ジン）いいぞ　２人とも。
Keep it up, boys.
壁にぶつかっても
新しい道を作ればいい。
Even if you hit a wall, just make a new path.
お前たちに作れない道など
ないんだ。→
I believe you can do that anytime.
パズルも…　人生も。
That applies to both puzzles and your lives.
ジンが　パズルを憎むなんて
ありえねえ。
I can't imagine he'd hate puzzles.
（イワシミズ君）
危険人物　接近。　危険人物　接近。→
Dangerous person approaching.
危険人物　接近！　危険人物　接近！
どうしたんだい？　イワシミズ君。→
What's wrong, Iwashimizu?
（拡声機）聞こえるか～？　カイト！
Can you hear me, Kaito?
ジン!?
アムギーネ共和国の紋章！
Jin?
That's Amgine's coat of arms!
（拡声機・ジン）俺と　パズルで戦え～！
Come puzzle with me!
What now, Kaito?
あっ　どうする気!?　カイト！
（ギャモン）待ちやがれ　バカイト！
Stop, Freakaito!
（アナ）カイト！
ちょっと待ちなさいよ！
Kaito!
Wait!
（イワシミズ君）ちょっと待ちなさいよ。
（キュービック）カイト…　うわっ！
Kaito!
（拡声機・ジン）
臆せず　やって来たな！　カイト！→
I'm glad you came, Kaito!
さすが
俺の教え子だけの事はある。
Just as I'd expect from my student.
どうした？　驚きのあまり
言葉が出ないか？
What's wrong? Cat got your tongue?
ジン！　記憶が戻ったのか!?
Did your memories return, Jin?
ああ！　だからこそ
今ここに　こうして　俺はいる！
Yeah! That's why I'm here!
（拡声機・ジン）ファイ・ブレインの
子供たちを　パズルで滅ぼす。
I'll destroy the children of the Phi Brain using puzzles.
Kaito! Be proud that you'll get to die by my own hands!
カイト！　この俺によって
抹殺される事を誇らしく思え！
まさか…　まさかジンが！
No way... No way, Jin!
まさか…　そんなバカな…。
I can't believe this... Impossible!
（イワシミズ君のスピーカー）
こんなの夢だ…　幻だ！
This can't be real! Tell me it's a dream!
カイト…。
Kaito...
Tell me it's a joke, Jin!
うそだ！
うそだと言ってくれ　ジン！
な～んてな！
何!?
As if.
What?
お前がジンじゃない事ぐらい
お見通しなんだよ！
It's quite obvious you're not Jin!
ジンさんじゃないって？
思うに　パチもん。
It's not Jin?
I think... he's a fake.
お…　俺が偽者だって？
何の事か…。
You're saying I'm a fake? What the hell?
ふざけんな！
Cut it out already.
もしかして　マスターブレインのやつらが
言ってるジンってぇのは→
Are you the "Jin" the Master Brain jerks talked about?
おめえの事なんじゃねえのか!?
そう思ってくれるとしたら
光栄だよ！→
Would be nice if they did!
あのお方は　私の宝物だからね！
He's my treasure, you know!
あっ。
お前！
あいつ…。
You?
That bastard...
（拡声機）真方ジン様！　私は
あなたを世界唯一の師とあがめ→
Makata Jin!
I accept you as the one and only true master of the world,
師との盟約により　パズラーを
せん滅する誓いを立てし者！
and as per my contract with my master, I'll annihilate all puzzlers!
I devote my soul and body to you! I'm the greatest genius Giver among the Master Brains,
身も心も　あなたに捧げた
マスターブレイン随一の天才ギヴァー→
その名も　まさに　真逆ジン！
the one and only Masaka Jin!
Masaka?! So he's the one back there making the Einstein face...
マサカ!?　って事は
あの時の　アッカンベー太郎は…。
真方ジン様　あなたの目の前で
大門カイトを倒せる事→
I can imagine no greater honor than destroying Daimon Kaito in front of you, my lord!
真逆ジン　この上なき幸せ。→
どうか　その目で
しっかり　お見届け下さい！
Please play close attention to this!
ザケんな　偽もん！
Dream on, fake! I'll solve your lame puzzle in three seconds!
お前のパズルなんか
俺が３秒で解いてやるぜ！
ハッ！　面白い。
ならば　そのコントローラーを取れ！
You're a riot!
Then take that controller!
（拡声機・真逆）この巨大パズルは→
This giant puzzle is a combination of a slider and a maze.
迷路と　スライドパズルの
二重構造になっている。
You must move the blocks using that controller and find the way to the exit.
（真逆）お前は　コントローラーで
ブロックを動かしながら→
対角線上にある
ゴールを目指すのだ。→
ただし　制限時間内に
たどりつけなければ…。
However, if you can't make it before the time is up...
たどりつけなければ？
What then?
落ちる！
Then you fall!
ヒャーッハハハハハ！　ハハハハハハ！
Puzzle time start!
パズルタイムの始まりだ！
（真逆）ウハーッハハハ…　ゴホッ　ゴホッ。
ここが　入り口か。
So this is the entrance?
え～っと…。
Let's see...
ハハハ…。　仮に　解き方が
分かったとしても→
Even if you know how to solve it,
タイムリミットに間に合うかな？
can you make it in time?
手こずってるな…。
He's taking too long.
偽者なんかに負けるな　カイト！
（キュービック）だけど→
Don't lose to a fake, Kaito!
Even if he's just a fake,
偽者とはいえ　あいつが
見た目だけじゃなく→
if he copied not only Makata Jin's looks but also his puzzle skills...
真方ジンのパズル能力まで
完璧に　コピーしてるとしたら…。
それは　ないわ！→
He can't do that.
Ain't half bad for a faker's puzzle!
なかなか　やるじゃねえか。
偽もんのパズルにしてはよ！
ヘヘヘ…。　減らず口も　今のうちだ！
You won't be talking big like that for much longer!
There isn't enough time.
時間が足りねえ…。
It looks like he's taking the longer path.
なんか　遠回りしてるみたい。
いや　あれでいい。
えっ？　だって…。
No. It's the right one.
Why?
カイトのやつ
ちゃんと気付いてやがる。
He noticed it too.
だが…。
ブロックを動かすだけなら　ともかく→
Moving the blocks is one thing, but having a complicated maze as well is too much.
中が　細かい迷路になってるなんて
複雑すぎるよ。
でも　それだけじゃない。
まだ　何か隠れてる。
That's not all. Something else is hidden there.
間に合いそうだぜ！
I'm gonna make it in time!
うっ…。　させるか！
No chance!
てめえは　やっぱ偽もんだ！
You really are a fake!
ジンは　こんな
卑怯な手は使わねえ！
Jin would never resort to cowardly moves like this!
ちが～う！
断じて卑怯なのではな～い！
Nope! There's nothing cowardly about this!
勝利のためなら
どんな手段をも　いとわない！
Win by any means necessary! That's what Makata Jin teaches!
それが　真方ジン様の教えなのだ！
うわっ!?　野郎…。
Damn bastard!
見えた！
Got it!
I'll rotate it even more!
もっと大きく傾けねば！
カイト！
Kaito!
行けるか？
I have to risk it...
間に合ったぜ。
I made it!
He won!
やった～！
おわっ！　ちょ…　おま…。
Yay, he won!
カイト　よかった～！
さすが　僕のカイトだね。
That's my Kaito for you.
そ…　そんな…。
あと一歩だったのに～！
Geez! I was just one step away!
まさか　この私が…
真逆ジンが破れるとは…。
I can't... I can't believe I lost...
あっ!?　あっ　待て…　あっ！
Wait! Wait!
（ギャモン）カイト。　お前の　真方ジンへの
気持ちは分からなかねえ。
Kaito. I understand your feelings for Makata Jin,
だが　レイツェルが転校してきた
だけじゃなく→
but not only did Raetsel transfer here, we even have a fake Makata Jin to deal with.
真方ジンの偽者まで
出てきたんだぜ。→
こりゃ　ただごとじゃねえぞ。
We can't just ignore this.
どうするの？
マスターブレインが　次々　襲ってきたら。
What do we do if the Master Brains keep attacking?
（ギャモン）
上等じゃねえか。　俺が倒す！
That'd be great! I'll take them all down!
いや…　全てのパズルは　俺が解く。
No.
I'm gonna solve all the puzzles.
No! Me!
バカ！　俺だ！
俺だ！
俺だっつってんだろうが！
Me!
I'm telling you it'll be me!
You're so hyped. Did something good happen?
テンション高ぇな。
何か　いい事あったのかよ!?
I can't say it now!
Enough of that.
バカ　ここに…。　言えねえよ！
はいはい　そこまで。
What was the point of that puzzle battle?
（レイツェル）あのパズルバトルに
何の意味があったの!?
（エニグマ）まあ　そんなに
怒らない　怒らない。→
Don't make such a fuss.
It's not like the Master Brains only act on my orders.
マスターブレインの行動を全て　私が把握
しているわけではないんだよ。
大門カイトは　私が倒すわ。
そういう契約だから。
I'll defeat Daimon Kaito. That's my end of the contract.
だといいんだが…。
If you can.
あっ　いや…　なに→
I mean, if you can maintain your composure with Makata Jin around.
真方ジンのそばに
いる事によって→
君の戦意が
失われなければよいがとね…。
フン。　そうかもね。
You might be right.
I hope you are jesting.
おいおい　冗談だろ？
そっちこそ。
So do I.
フッ。　大人をからかうなんて
悪い子だ。
Good girls don't make gibes at adults.
Preview
Let's have a barbecue.